Guide to the Labor Unions Reference Collection, 1958-2001
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Labor Unions Reference collection 1958-2001
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
0.5 Linear Feet 500 Items
Collection contains materials such as newspaper clippings, flyers, publicly-distributed memoranda, form-letters, and agreement books pertaining to the organization and unionization of Duke’s non-academic employees. The collection ranges in date from 1965-2001 with bulk dates of 1965-1979. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The University Archives Labor Union collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources, including the Employee Union Local 77, AFSCME, AFL-CIO, Employee Union Local 465, and Employee Union 1199 D.
Historical Note
The Duke Employees Benevolent Society was formed in February 1965. It became affiliated with the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), AFofL, in August, 1965, as Local 77. Collection contains materials, such as, newspaper clippings, flyers, publicly-distributed memoranda, form-letters, and agreement books pertaining to the organization and unionization of Duke's non-academic employees. The collection ranges in date from 1965-2001 with bulk dates of 1965-1979. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
Collection contains materials such as newspaper clippings, flyers, publicly-distributed memoranda, form-letters, and agreement books pertaining to the organization and unionization of Duke’s non-academic employees. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century
Labor unions -- North Carolina -- Durham
Related Material
Don Roy Papers, 1921 - 1980
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - The Worker's Chronicle, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1965-1979
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1980-2001
  - Unidentified [Miscellaneous publications], 1968, 1970, 1982
  - Local 77 AFSCME - History, 1965
  - Progressive Labor Party, 1975-1977
  - University Administration Memoranda, 1970-1979
  - Local 132F ATU (Amalgamated Transit Union), 1994
  - Local 77 AFSCME, 1965-1969
  - Faculty and Student Groups, 1966-1968; 1975; 1979; [199?]
  - Unions, general, 1958 reprint
  - Local 77 AFSCME, 1970-1979; undated
  - Local 77 AFSCME - Agreements, 1972; 1975
  - Local 465 IUOE (International Union of Operating Engineers), 1973-1982
  - Miscellaneous Groups, 1975-1979
  - Service Employees Council, [1969]
  - Local 1199D, 1969-1970